<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>algorithms on Girish Varma</title>
    <link>https://girishvarma.in/projects/algorithms/</link>
    <description>Recent content in algorithms on Girish Varma</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://girishvarma.in/projects/algorithms/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title> Physarum Can Compute Shortest Paths</title>
      <link>https://girishvarma.in/publication/slime-mold2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://girishvarma.in/publication/slime-mold2/</guid>
      <description>Physarum polycephalum is a slime mold that is apparently able to solve shortest path problems. A mathematical model has been proposed by Tero et al. (Journal of Theoretical Biology, 244, 2007, pp. 553–564) to describe the feedback mechanism used by the slime mold to adapt its tubular channels while foraging two food sources s0 and s1. We prove that, under this model, the mass of the mold will eventually converge to the shortest path of the network that the mold lies on, independently of the structure of the network or of the initial mass distribution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streaming Algorithms for Language Recognition Problems</title>
      <link>https://girishvarma.in/publication/streaming2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://girishvarma.in/publication/streaming2/</guid>
      <description>We study the complexity of the following problems in the streaming model. Membership testing for DLIN We show that every language in DLIN can be recognised by a randomized one-pass O(logn) space algorithm with inverse polynomial one-sided error, and by a deterministic p-pass O(n/p) space algorithm. We show that these algorithms are optimal.Membership testing for LL(k). For languages generated by LL(k) grammars with a bound of r on the number of nonterminals at any stage in the left-most derivation, we show that membership can be tested by a randomized one-pass O(rlogn) space algorithm with inverse polynomial (in n) one-sided error.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>