<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>hardness-of-approximation on Girish Varma</title>
    <link>https://girishvarma.in/projects/hardness-of-approximation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in hardness-of-approximation on Girish Varma</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://girishvarma.in/projects/hardness-of-approximation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hardness of Approximate Coloring</title>
      <link>https://girishvarma.in/publication/thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://girishvarma.in/publication/thesis/</guid>
      <description>The graph coloring problem is a notoriously hard problem, for which we do not have efficient algorithms. A coloring of a graph is an assignment of colors to its vertices such that the end points of every edge have different colors. A k-coloring is a coloring that uses at most k distinct colors. The graph coloring problem is to find a coloring that uses the minimum number of colors. Given a 3-colorable graph, the best known efficient algorithms output an n0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Characterization of Hard-to-cover CSPs</title>
      <link>https://girishvarma.in/publication/characterization-covering/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://girishvarma.in/publication/characterization-covering/</guid>
      <description>We continue the study of covering complexity of constraint satisfaction problems (CSPs) initiated by Guruswami, Hastad and Sudan [SIAM J. Computing, 31(6):1663&amp;ndash;1686, 2002] and Dinur and Kol [In Proc. 28th IEEE Conference on Computational Complexity, 2013]. The covering number of a CSP instance $\phi$, denoted by ν(Φ) is the smallest number of assignments to the variables of $\phi$, such that each constraint of Φ is satisfied by at least one of the assignments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Super-polylogarithmic hypergraph coloring hardness via low-degree long codes</title>
      <link>https://girishvarma.in/publication/hyper-coloring-journal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://girishvarma.in/publication/hyper-coloring-journal/</guid>
      <description>We prove improved inapproximability results for hypergraph coloring using the low-degree polynomial code (aka, the &amp;lsquo;short code&amp;rsquo; of Barak et. al. [FOCS 2012]) and the techniques proposed by Dinur and Guruswami [FOCS 2013] to incorporate this code for inapproximability results. In particular, we prove quasi-NP-hardness of the following problems on $n$-vertex hyper-graphs:
 Coloring a 2-colorable 8-uniform hypergraph with $2^{2^{\Omega(loglog\sqrt{n})}}$ colors. Coloring a 4-colorable 4-uniform hypergraph with $2^{2^{\Omega(loglog\sqrt{n})}}$ colors. Coloring a 3-colorable 3-uniform hypergraph with $(log n)^{\Omega(1/logloglog n)}$ colors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reducing uniformity in Khot-Saket hypergraph coloring hardness reductions</title>
      <link>https://girishvarma.in/publication/improved-khot-saket/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://girishvarma.in/publication/improved-khot-saket/</guid>
      <description>In a recent result, Khot and Saket [FOCS 2014] proved the quasi-NP-hardness of coloring a 2-colorable 12-uniform hypergraph with 2(logn)Ω(1) colors. This result was proved using a novel outer PCP verifier which had a strong soundness guarantee. In this note, we show that we can reduce the arity of their result by modifying their 12-query inner verifier to an 8-query inner verifier based on the hypergraph coloring hardness reductions of Guruswami et.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Derandomized Graph Product Results using the Low Degree Long Code</title>
      <link>https://girishvarma.in/publication/graph-prods/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://girishvarma.in/publication/graph-prods/</guid>
      <description>In this paper, we address the question of whether the recent derandomization results obtained by the use of the low-degree long code can be extended to other product settings. We consider two settings: (1) the graph product results of Alon, Dinur, Friedgut and Sudakov [GAFA, 2004] and (2) the \&amp;ldquo;majority is stablest\&amp;rdquo; type of result obtained by Dinur, Mossel and Regev [SICOMP, 2009] and Dinur and Shinkar [In Proc. APPROX, 2010] while studying the hardness of approximate graph coloring.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>